我扣不上这个纽扣
I can't do this button.
喔 只差一点
Oh, you almost got it.
只差一点
Almost got it.
那声音...
The sound...
人们说话的声音
of the people talking.
嗯?
Hmm?
- 是降A调,- 是吗? 好吧
- It's a flat.- Is it? Well.
看看你多聪明 对吧?
Look how smart you are, huh?
- 我们走,- 我们走
- Here we go.- Here we go.
谢谢
Thank you.
我很荣幸为你们介绍我的儿子,Patrick Obyedkov
I am proud to introduce my son to you, Patrick Obyedkov.
25年前 Patrick还在四年级
25 years ago, patrick was in the fourth grade.
是个好学生 打少年棒球
A good student, played little league.
后来发生了那场车祸
And then there was the accident.
现在我们在此...
And here we are...
为有类似精神残障的人筹集善款
Raising money for people with similar neurological disabilities.
希望你们喜爱这次音乐会
I hope you enjoy the concert.
你准备好了吗?
Are you all set?
准备好了
All set.
他从来没弹错一个音符过
He's never missed a note.
情况不对
Something's wrong.
Patrick 怎么回事?
Patrick, what is it?
我的手 好痛
My hand, it hurts.
让我看看
Let me see it.
哦 爸爸!
Oh, papa!
-=怪杰医生豪斯=-,第三季 第15集 "聪明半颗心"; "Half Wit"
House M.D.Season 3 Episode 15 "Half Wit"
"早上好 现在就读 很奇特 妈妈留"
"Good Morning, Read now. XO Yoyo Mama.
什么紧急情况?
What's the emergency?
35岁的学者综合症患者 左手肌张力障碍
35-year-old savant, dystonia in his left hand.
他一大早五点钟呼叫我们就为了那个?
He paged us at 5:00 in the morning for that?
我回去睡觉了 肌张力障碍没有生命威胁
I'm going back to bed. Dystonia's not life-threatening.
氯硝西泮就行
Clonazepam will take care of it.
他已经在用氯硝西泮了,(治疗肌肉抽动)
He's already on clonazepam.
因他自从10岁那场巴士车祸之后,就一直有癫痫症状
For seizures he has from a bus accident when he was ten.
那就用苯托品
Then we treat with benztropine.
怎么了?
What's up?
35岁的学者综合症患者 肌张力障碍
35-year-old savant, dystonia.
我要回去睡觉了
I'm going back to bed.
你要去哪儿?
Where are you going?
洗手间 憋着也行
Bathroom. It can wait.
没什么大不了的 House
There is no case, House.
虽然肌张力障碍曾经是个医学谜团
Even if dystonia was some big medical mystery,
现在已经不是了
it's not this time.
难道你不觉得奇怪 一个完全健康
You're not intrigued as to how a perfectly healthy
从没有音乐训练的十岁男孩
ten-year-old boy with no prior musical training
在上学路上发生车祸后
gets into an accident on his way to school,
就突然能弹钢琴
can suddenly play the piano?
非要在早餐之前解决,一个25年之久的案例吗?
Do we have to solve a 25-year-old case before breakfast?
你们两个一起冲澡了?
You two shower together?
- 不是!,- 双重否定 那就是承认了
No! Double negative, it's a yes.
学者综合症
Savantism is just one of those things.
是解释不通的病症
It's inexplicable.
含糊不清不代表无法解释
Just because it's inexplicited, doesn't mean it's inexplicable.
我想要新测试
I want new labs.
全血球计数及血小板检查,甲状腺和肾上腺功能测试
CBC with platelets, CH panel, thyroid and adrenal function tests.
为什么?
For what?
我不知道
I don't know.
举起左手
Raise your left hand.
那是右手
That's your right hand.
你们在查什么?
What are you looking for?
只是想确保 发生过的不要再发生
Just wanna make sure whatever happened doesn't happen again.
- 往上推,- 往上推
Push up. Push up.
他重复别人的话
He repeats what people say.
这是种补偿机制
It's a compensation mechanism.
他知道他应该说的什么
He knows he's supposed to say something,
所以他就重复刚听到的话
so he repeats what he just heard.
那很好 说明他用心了
That's good, shows he's engaged.
脊柱没问题
Spine's okay.
好了
All right.
现在舌头像这样伸出来 跟我做
Now stick out your tongue like this, copy me.
你的舌头好大
You have a big tongue.
我知道 很搞笑 但是跟我做
I know, it's funny, but copy me.
Radcliff路在整修
There was construction on Radcliff.
我只好下车 穿着高跟鞋走了一英里多
So I had to get out of the car and, and walk in high heels for over a mile.
Radcliff?
和哪条马路相交?
What was the cross street?
有关系吗?
Does it matter?
我不知道 又不是我提起来的
I don't know, I'm not the one who brought it up.
把这个绑上
Tie this off.
绑紧了
Nice and tight.
这和我的脚有什么关系吗?
Does this have anything to do with my foot?
你长了个水疱
You have a blister.
你不该用水疱来浪费医生的时间
You don't waste a doctor's time with a blister.
该用更严重的事来浪费医生的时间
You waste a doctor's time with more important things.
比如你嘴里那股阴沟般的气味
Like the sewer that's being vented out of your mouth.
我的口气?
My breath?
如果你不呼气 对我们两个都好
If you could stop doing that, we'd all be grateful.
我不能不呼吸
I can't stop breathing.
- 的确 但是你可以停止催吐了,- 我没有...
- No, but you could stop puking.- I don't--
你嘴上说着"不" 你突节的手指说"厄啊"
Your lips say, "no," your gnarly fingers say, "blegh!"
可以开始了
It's good to go.
真可惜
It's a shame.
你这么瘦真的很可爱
You do look cute that thin.
运动皮质区看起来没问题
Motor cortex looks good.
每样都查过了
Everything checks out.
你做了哪些测试?
What tests did you run?
神经学上的都做了...
Full battery of neurological--
我要验血做胆固醇和葡萄糖水平测试
I need this blood checked for cholesterol and glucose levels.
病人的问题在脚上
Patient had a foot problem.
另外的病人
Different patient.
里面没有别人
There was no one else in there.
你用错仪器了
You're using the wrong equipment.
Foreman医生 我以为我们可以出院了
Dr. Foreman, I thought we were being discharged.
我是House医生
I'm Dr. House.
以防Foreman医生没有提起过我
On the off chance that Dr. Foreman didn't mention it,
我也是有点天赋的
I have something of a gift too.
来吧
Come on.
- 轮到你了,- 轮到我了
- Your turn.- My turn.
这和他的手有什么关系吗?
Does this have anythingto do with his hand?
有可能 好了 Patrick 闭上眼睛
It might. Okay, Patrick, close your eyes.
这是什么?
What's this?
- d调 g降调 a降调 b调 c调,- 好了
- D, g flat, a flat, b, c-,- Yeah, all right, all right.
他很不错
He's good.
可以让他走了吗?
Can we let him go?
他太棒了
He's great.
他得留下
He's staying.
通知放射科
Call radiology.
做脑部核磁共振
I need a functional MRI of his brain.
功能磁共振成像看不出外伤
FMRI's not gonna show trauma.
我不是在找外伤
I'm not looking for trauma.
我想看看音乐
I wanna see the music.
看看音乐
See the music.
真是无聊
Well, that's dull.
你觉得功能磁共振成像会显出一个大箭头
You think FMRI's gonna show a big arrow
指向写着"学者综合症"的闪光标志?
pointing to a flashing sign saying "savantism"?
那就帮上大忙了
Would be hugely helpful.
不知何故 他变成了一个音乐专家
Somehow, he's been rewired as a music specialist.
我想知道是怎么发生的
I wanna know how that happens.
他调用了你不能调用的那部分脑子
He has access to parts of the brain that you don't.
他的脑子没什么反应
His brain's doing nothing.
听到音乐 反应和别的傻瓜一样
It looks like any jerk listening.
他不是聆听方面的天才
He's not a savant at listening.
他是演奏方面的天才
He's a savant at playing.
听和弹是两种不同的脑部活动
Well, listening and playing are two different neurological processes.
把音乐关了
Turn off the music.
Patrick 我要你把你的腿想象成钢琴
Patrick, I want you to pretend that your leg is a piano.
我的腿不是钢琴
My leg's not a piano.
我知道 所以我才说"想象成"
I know, that's why I said "pretend".
这小子是个低能儿
The kid's a moron.
头别动 用你的手指
Keep your head still, use your fingers.
哇 真酷 对吧?
Wow. Cool, huh?
他的心率变高了
His heart rate rose.
情绪上的反应?
Emotional response?
那为什么缘脑不活跃呢?
Then why is there no activity in the limbic system?
除非他的心脏有问题
Unless there's a problem with his heart.
做个超声心动图来确认
Do an echo to confirm.
给他洗洗 他需要手术
- Then scrub up.- He's gonna need surgery.
不是肌张力障碍
Wasn't dystonia.
他有心脏问题 导致手臂上的动脉收缩
He's got a heart condition that caused the arteries in his arm to constrict.
你知道为什么House要去波士顿吗?
Do you have any idea why House would want to go to Boston?
去喝杂烩汤? (波士顿海鲜有名)
The chowder?
这个礼拜五的机票
Plane tickets, this Friday.
我看了他的信
I opened his mail.
听说哈佛有个传染病学的主任医生讲座
I heard there's an opening at Harvard for division chief, infectious disease.
上进求知不是他的特色
Well, ambition's not one of his more prominent traits.
- 尽管...- 什么?
- Although...- what?
他在门诊时做了血样检查
Well, he was testing blood in the clinic.
我不觉得那是病人的血
Don't think it was a patient's blood.
为什么 血是绿色的?
Why, it was green?
不 他做了些常规检查
No, he was checking for routine stuff.
有可能他是为了新工作 做基本健康证明
Makes sense if he's lookingfor basic medical clearance for employment.
我要回家
I'm going home.
你不许回去
No, you're not.
他随时都可能出现
He could show up any minute.
他沉迷于学者综合症患者呢
Not with a savant to obsess about.
我来查这里
I'll take in here.
卧室在客厅后面
Bedroom's down the hall.
你来过这里?
You've been here?
卧室还能在哪儿?
Where else would the bedroom be?
一起来?
Come with?
你怕他发现我们闯进他家
You're scared of him catching us breaking into his home,
却不怕他发现我们在他床上做那事儿?
but you're not scared of him catching us doing it in his bed?
反正不管怎样 我都会被炒鱿鱼...
If I'm gonna get fired anyway...
就快到心脏了
almost at the heart.
没有出血
No bleeding.
到了
And...done.
心率160 在加快
Heart rate's 160, it's accelerating.
到210了
He's at 210.
他有室上性心动过速
He's in supraventricular tachycardia.
电极板!
Paddles!
充电
Charging.
离手!
Clear!
我们在浪费时间!
We're wasting our time!
他的高中年册
His high school yearbook.
除非你认为他是去波士顿参加高中同学会
Unless you think he's going to Boston to attend a high school reunion,
否则就放回去 在他回家前离开
put it back and let's get out of here before he comes home.
他没有笑
He's not smiling.
我怀疑他没有牙齿
I wonder if he has teeth.
波士顿的区号是多少?
What's the area code for Boston?
617 怎么了?
617, why?
麻省综合医院 有什么可以帮您?
Massachusetts general. May I help you?
你以为可以轻而易举,把House医生偷过去吗?
Did you think you could steal Dr. House without a fight?
把他偷过去干吗?
Steal him for what?
不要和我耍嘴皮子 我知道他要去你那里
Quit jerking me around, I know he's coming out there.
我们没打算聘请他
We're not looking to hire him.
上个月他给你打了六次电话
He's called you six times in the last month.
我们没打算聘请他
We're not looking to hire him.
你重复说 我就会相信你了?
You think if you keep repeating it, I'll start believing you?
Cuddy医生 我没别的可说了
Dr.Cuddy, there's nothing else I can say.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
如果他不是为工作面试而去
Well, if he's not coming there for a job interview,
那他去你的医院
he's either coming to your hospital for
就是以普通病人的身份
a social visitor because he's a patient.
是这样的吗 Medick医生?
Is it a social visit, Dr.Medick?
我受不了House
I can't stand House.
Kupersmith医生也受不了
Neither can Dr.Kupersmith.
怎么了?
What's up?
你知道波士顿的Kupersmith医生吗?
Do you know a Dr.Kuper Smith in Boston?
知道 他是个肿瘤科医生
Yeah, he's an oncologist.
怎么了?
What's up?
他具体专攻哪方面的?
What's his subspecialty?
脑癌
Brain cancer.
发生了什么事?
What's going on?
他看起来没病啊
He doesn't look sick.
他应该有症状
He should have symptoms.
眼花 头疼 精神混乱 呆滞
Blurred vision, headaches, confusion, clumsiness.
那取决于癌的类型 程度 恶化速度
Depends on how far along the cancer is, what kind, how aggressive.
他没告诉过你
He didn't tell you.
House就是House
House is House.
他和别的癌症患者没两样
He's no different than anyone else with cancer.
一旦说了 那以后所有的对话都是关于癌
Once you tell, then every conversation is about that.
心脏骤停说明我们错了
Cardiac arrest means we were wrong.
肯定有心脏问题
There was a heart problem.
但不会有血管收缩!
But no vasoconstriction!
心脏问题不可能导致手的问题
The heart problem couldn't have caused the hand problem.
除非出血是突然出现的
Unless the bleed happened suddenly.
脑部缺乏供血可以解释肌张力障碍
Less blood to the brain explains the dystonia,
心脏缺乏供血可以解释心脏病发作
less blood to the heart explains the heart attack.
把他上上下下查个遍
Scope him above and below.
如果不起作用 剖开他
If that doesn't work, gut him.
你不能麻醉他?
You can't sedate him?
那样他的咽喉可能会萎陷
There's a risk his throat could collapse.
你看起来很生气 爸爸
You look mad, pop.
不 不 我没生气 我向你保证
No. No, I'm not mad, I promise you.
只是 那位医生要对你做的事
It's just that, um, the doctor has to do something
会很痛
to you and it's, and it's gonna hurt.
弄痛我?
Hurt me?
为什么要弄痛我?
Why hurt me?
让你好起来
Make you better.
我生了什么病?
What's wrong with me?
他们不知道
Well, they don't know.
Patrick 别担心 一切都会好好的
Patrick, don't you worry, everything is gonna be great.
好了 要开始了 Patrick
All right, here we go, Patrick.
你想要弄痛我
You wanna hurt me.
张开嘴 就像这样
Okay, open. Like this.
你只要看着我
You just look at me.
一切都会好起来的
And everythingis gonna be okay.
看着我 Patrick 看这边
Look at me. Patrick, over here.
是的 没问题的
Yep, it's okay.
没问题的 真的
It's okay, really.
Wilson医生 Wilson!
Dr.Wilson! Wilson!
我刚和Cuddy说过话 她不肯说
I just spoke to Cuddy, she can't confirm whether
House是否申请去波士顿工作
House is applying for a job in Boston.
啊 我要迟到了...
Yeah, I'm late for a--
如果我要重新找工作的话
If I have to look for work,
我有权知道
I have a right to know.
很美
That's pretty.
我初中的时候写的
I wrote this when I was in junior high school.
但是我怎么也不知道如何写下去
I could never figure out what came next.
然后那个傻瓜弹出了这个
Then dimwit came up with this.
这很好
It's good.
很完美
It's perfect.
我可以在雷雨天在屋顶上搭座塔
I could set up a tower on the roof during a lightning storm.
让你和你的病人互换脑子
Help you switch brains with your patient.
然后你就可以成为天才钢琴家
Then you would be the brilliant pianist
而他就成为患了脑癌,却不告诉朋友的医生
and he would be the doctor hiding brain cancer from his friend.
没什么的
It's nothing.
你得谈谈这个
You need to talka bout it.
至少让我看看你的病历
At least let me look at your medical file.
你真是无中生有
You're making a big deal out of nothing.
还有谁知道?
Who else knows?
没别人知道
No one.
还有癌症可不是"没什么"
And cancer isn't nothing.
抱歉 没有冒犯你的专业的意思
Sorry, didn't mean to offend your specialty.
你为什么不来找我?
Why didn't you come to me?
Stein很不错
Stein's good.
Stein接下来六个月都在非洲
Stein's in Africa for the next six months.
他说我至少还有六个月
He's given meat least six months.
我会去波士顿 我会接受治疗
I'll go to Boston, I'll get the treatment.
然后万事安好
Everything'll be fine.
没必要谈什么的
No need to talka bout it.
你是对的 主刀医生在肾后面发现了一处出血
You're right, surgeon found a bleed behind the kidney
在腹膜后隙 原因不明
in the retroperitoneal cavity, but no reason for it.
没有癌 没有动脉破裂...
No cancer, no ruptured arteries...
那么出血解释了症状
so bleeding explains the symptoms,
但解释不了出血
but we've got no explanation for the bleeding.
在他们缝合他的时候
And while they were closing him up,
Patrick出现了严重的癫痫
Patrick had a grand mal seizure,
让人毫无头绪 因为他服用抗惊厥药物
which makes no sense, since he's on an anti-convulsant medication.
你告诉他了
You told him.
不 我没有
No, I didn't.
我 只告诉了Cameron
I...only told Cameron.
好吧 你们非常聪明地推断出我有癌症
Okay. You guys have cleverly deduced that I have cancer.
你们没有权利知道
You have no right to know.
你们无需知道
You have no business knowing.
我们想要做些血样测试
We'd like to run some blood tests.
只要是为了病人做就行 而不是我!
As soon as you work up our patient, who is not me!
我们只是想确认你没有被误诊
We just want to make sure you weren't misdiagnosed.
我没有 不谈了
I wasn't, let's move on.
我们只想抽几管血
We're just asking for a couple of vials.
- 不需要 - 为什么?
- No!,- Why not?
好吧 假装我完全健康 继续做事吧
Okay, we're going to proceed as if I'm perfectly healthy.
明明知道不是的 要怎么装?
How can we do that if we know you're not?
你们什么都不知道!
You don't know anything!
最好知道 服用抗惊厥药的病人
Except, hopefully, how a patient on
怎么会发生癫痫?
anti-convulsant medication has a seizure.
抗惊厥药不能避免癫痫
Anti-seizure meds don't prevent seizures,
只是控制癫痫
they just make them manageable.
根据手术医生的报告
According to the surgeon's report,
连控制都谈不上
this one wasn't even close to manageable.
说明问题不在于为什么会发作癫痫
Means the question isn't why is he having seizures,
而是为什么癫痫会恶化?
it's why are his seizures getting worse?
什么变化了?
What's changed?
他的大脑 恶化了
His brain, it's gotten worse.
那让它更加恶化
So we make it even worser.
停掉他的抗惊厥药
We take him off anti-convulsant medication.
癫痫会发作得更厉害
He'll seize even more.
多次癫痫发作会严重损害大脑
Multiple seizures can seriously damage a brain.
这家伙都扣扣子都有问题
Dude can't button his shirt.
还能有更严重的脑损伤?
How much more damaged we really talking about?
更强的癫痫会照亮大脑的不同部分
Stronger seizures will light up different parts of
说明哪里受损
the brain which will indicate which parts are damaged.
一旦恶化 做正电子体层摄影
Once he gets worse, do a PET scan.
正电子体层摄影做好了?
PET scan done?
- 不,- 你来安慰我情绪?
No. You come for my feelings?
可惜我把它丢在另一条裤子里了
'Cause I left them in my other pants.
这是一封推荐信
This is a letter of recommendation.
我在申请一份在宾州的工作
I'm applying for a job at Penn.
谢谢你自己撰稿
Thank you for writing your own.
我的想法肯定被完美呈现了
I'm sure my thoughts are beautifully phrased.
谢谢你的签名
Thank you for signing it.
省得我伪造签名
Saves me having to fake your signature.
离Weiss远点
Stay away from weiss.
他会和病人一起哭
He cries with his patients.
在病人死时握着他们的手
Holds their hands as they die.
他不会喜欢你的
He won't like you.
你刚学会冷淡面对癌症
Your new found nonchalance in the face of cancer.
我以为你会觉得这是可喜的进步
I thought you'd find it appealing.
20 秒
20 seconds.
很不错
Pretty good.
怎么讲?
For what?
从冷漠的混蛋变得有人性花的时间
Time it took you to go from hard-ass to human being.
你真的想走?
You really wanna leave?
如果你不在了 留在这儿也没什么意义
If you're not here, there's not much point in staying.
我还没死呢
I'm not dead yet.
你想干什么?
What are you doing?
就知道你会觉得很诱惑
I know this must be a turn-on for you.
小荡妇骗吻 为了扎我一针
Little whorishto kiss and stab.
你回吻了
You kissed back.
我不想你到死都不知道被我吻是什么感觉
I didn't want you to die without knowing the feeling.
事实上 没有哪个女人应该为此抱憾终身
Actually, no woman should die without knowing the feeling.
我们要的不过是几滴血
All we need is a few drops of your blood.
Foreman和Chase的嘴唇别想靠这么近
Foreman and Chase's lips are not gonna get
我知道你们的阴谋了
so close now that I know your plan.
楼下有个护士不惜丢掉工作
There's a nurse downstairs about to risk his job
- 要偷到你自己抽的那管血,- 是的
to steal the blood you drew from yourself yes--
我的编号020406
I'm patient number 020406.
以luke N.Laura名字保存在记录室
In the record room under the name Luke N.Laura.
那儿有一整管的血
There's a whole vial of blood there.
断层扫描 核磁共振 脑脊液检查,所有你需要的
Along with CT scans, MRIs, CSF--everything you need.
需要精子样本的话 来找我时别拿针了
If you need a sperm sample, come back without the needle.
中脑脊部有六厘米的聚块
Six centimeter mass in his dorsal midbrain,
延伸到颞页
extending into the temporal lobe.
无法手术
That's inoperable.
他还有多长时间?
What kind of time does he have?
有一年
He's got a year.
护士 护士!
Nurse! Nurse!
有一份波士顿来的癌症药物试验同意书
There's a consent from Boston for the cancer drug trial.
有前期试验的描述吗?
Any description of the process of previous trials?
- 有,- 有效么?
Yep. Any chance it'd work?
不 甚至不是用来治疗癌症的
No. It's not even designed to work.
那他为什么要--
Why would he--
是用来治疗癌症晚期病人的抑郁
It's designed to treat depression in terminal cancer patients.
他好像不怎么抑郁
He doesn't seem depressed.
好吧 假设我快死了
Okay, let's assume that I am dying.
之前我明确要求你们不要这么假设
Which I specifically told you not to assume.
能否至少不要假设我明天就死?
Could we at least assume that'm not dying tomorrow?
而这个孩子 PET扫描显示他有几个病灶
Whereas this kid, PET revealed several more hot spots,
但都不明确
but they're non-specific.
你怎么还能全神贯注于他?
How can you focus on him?
这是我应付危机的唯一办法
It's the only way I can cope.
PET扫描还显示左脑工作卖力
Pet also showed a left brain that's working hard.
比右脑更卖力?
Harder than the right?
要不是这样 它才不值得一提
Wouldn't be worth mentioning otherwise.
颅内出血
Bleeding in the brain.
出血刺激皮层 引起癫痫恶化
Blood would irritate the lining, might cause the seizures to get worse.
是的 需要血管造影检查颅内脉管系统
Yes, he needs an angiogram to look at the vasculature inside his brain.
等这里忙完 我们就去做
We'll get right on it, as soon as we're finished here.
不劳驾了 我明白啦
Don't get up. I got it.
你们正忙呢 继续
You're busy. Continue.
知道我的手下正在做什么吗?
You know what my team is doing right now?
不知道
No.
他们正绞尽脑汁研究我有什么病
They're trying to figure out what's wrong with me.
你有什么病?
What's wrong with you?
谢谢关心
Thanks for asking.
他们发现我要死了
They found out that I'm dying.
真可悲
That's sad.
每个人都要死
Everyone's dying.
真可悲
That's sad.
明天流星也许会砸在我头上 自有天数
Meteor lands on my head tomorrow, it's all academic.
我告诉过他们别管我 但他们能吗?
I told them to leave me alone, but did they?
他们能吗?
D-did they?
不 那句是修辞用的
No, that one was rhetorical.
不 他们不能
Oh. No, they did not.
见鬼 脑子受伤前 你究竟什么样?
What the hell were you before you hit your head?
见鬼是个不好的词
Hell is a bad word.
混蛋和婊子也是
So's ass and bitch.
我大概能一气报出50个更复杂更脏的词
I could probably rattle off 50 much more complicated and disgusting ones,
你爸肯定对我大光其火
but then your dad would get pissed at me.
你喜欢你的生活吗?
Do you like your life?
什么生活?
What life?
你的生活
Your life.
弹钢琴 巡演
Playing the piano, going on tour.
女孩们左拥右抱
Scoring girls left and right.
我不喜欢女孩
I don't like girls.
男孩 不管什么能让你激动的
Boys. Whatever gets you off.
我喜欢钢琴
I like the piano.
有什么不对吗?
What's wrong?
Peter hayes医生?
Dr.Peter Hayes?
我是普林斯顿教学医院的Eric Foreman
This is Eric Foreman at Princeton Plainsboro.
你在进行一项,信号转导通路抑制剂的临床试验
You're doing a signal transduction inhibitor clinical trial.
现在进展如何-
What kind of results have you been--
转导通路抑制剂还要十几年呢
Transduction inhibitors are a decade away.
再见 Pete!
Bye, Pete!
杜克还有一个药物试验
They've got another trial going on at Duke.
15%的试验者存活期超过5年
15% extend their lives beyond five years.
如果你的蛋白phf为阳性的话-
If you're positive for protein phf--
别试着拯救我了
stop trying to save me.
我很好
I'm fine.
磁共振血管造影证实小块的血液凝集
MRA confirms small collections of blood
遍布在Patrick右半脑的白质上
throughout the white matter of Patrick's right hemisphere.
介意花点时间讨论下这个问题吗?
Mind if we chat about that for a few moments?
创伤 动脉瘤 癌症,自身免疫疾病都有可能
Either trauma, an aneurysm, cancer, or autoimmune disease.
我们需要做活组织检查才能确定
We need a biopsy to figure out which it is.
他的脑电图没有显示异常
His eeg was non-specific.
你要活检哪里?
Where are you gonna biopsy?
所有地方
Everywhere.
是 蒙着眼睛在脑子里乱弹琴摸索
Sure, just put on a blindfold and play piano in the tail on the brain.
他的颅内正在出血
He's bleeding into his brain.
他快死了
He's dying.
你不能在颞页随机扎针
You can't just randomly stab the temporal lobe
寄希望于扎对地方
and hope you hit the right spot.
我只要取一小块
Well, I'm only gonna take little tiny pieces.
直到什么时候?
Until what?
直到找到问题所在
Till I find the problem.
你会弄死他
Or you kill him.
不 就算他死了我还会继续查
No, I'll keep going even if I kill him.
他就完了
Then he's screwed.
感谢陪我聊天
Thanks for the chat.
如果我们做颅内脑电图呢?
What if we do the EEG from inside his brain?
我觉得有点被侮辱了
I'm actually a little insulted.
你们本该在上个小时里担心我
You were supposed to spend the last hour worrying about me.
这是侵入性的 有风险
It's risky and invasive.
那是上帝发明长长的同意书的原因
But that's why god invented the long consent form.
你能解释这主意高明在哪吗?
Can you get to why this is a brilliant idea?
如果有多处结构异常 外部脑电图就会模糊不清
External EEG could get confused if there are multiple structural abnormalities.
如果做颅内脑电图 就会知道哪做活检
If we perform the EEG inside the skull, it could show us where to biopsy.
高明
Brilliant.
去 做
Go. Do.
我还想和你谈谈关于-
I'd also like to talk to you about--
有关我个人 对吧?
This is gonna be personal, isn't it?
是的
Yeah.
我们用小钻头进入颅骨
We use a small drill to get inside the skull.
颅内有出血对吗?
There's bleeding inside?
是的
Yes.
只要钻12个孔
As long as we have 12 holes,
就能植入电极
we can surgically implant the electrodes
在紧贴大脑的脑膜下
under the meninges against the brain.
这不是癌症就是自体免疫病?
And it's either cancer or autoimmune disease?
- 恐怕是,- 是
- Sorry.- Yeah.
哪种更好些?
Which one is better?
都不好
Neither.
嘿 切到什么?
Hey. Where do we cut?
先不说
We don't.
我有话要说
I need to say something.
- 我私人的,- 是的
- Something personal.- Yeah.
我走不了 因为病历里有我感兴趣的
And I can't leave because you've got something interesting in that file.
抱歉是的
Sorry.
你是那种傲慢到无法让人喜欢的混蛋
You're an arrogant ass who makes it impossible for anyone to like him,
喜欢惩罚无过之人-
by punishing people who don't deserve--
能不能直接跳到“但是”部分?
Can get to the "but" part of this speech?
但是我喜欢你
But I like you.
不 你不喜欢
No, you don't.
只是对我快死了这件事做出反应
You're just reacting to the perception of my death.
你要分清主次
You need to put things in order.
- 害怕愧疚-,- 你能闭嘴吗?
- Fear of guilt-,- Would you shut up?
看见了吧 我惹恼你了
See? I annoy you.
现在要么给我看结果,或者你想...
Now are you gonna give me the results, or are you gonna...
颅内脑电图显示没有电极异常
Intracranial EEG showed no electrical abnormalities.
意味着是自体免疫疾病
Which means it's autoimmune.
不 还显示他整个右脑已经脑死亡
No, it also showed his entire right hemisphere is brain dead.
你们这些家伙忙着担心我的时候
So...while you guys were worrying about me,
这孩子的半个脑子死了
half this kid's brain died.
唯一的安慰是并没有脑死
The only solace you should take from this is the fact that it didn't.
比起颅内脑电图 普通脑电图差远了
Garden variety EEG sucks compared to the in-brain variety,
但不会误诊脑死
but it's not gonna miss brain death.
他正在恶化
He's gotten worse.
没有那么糟
Not that much worse.
呼吸受抑制 癫痫发作还在增加
Respiration is depressed, seizures are increasing,
五分钟一次
one every five minutes.
还不算太糟
It's not that much worse.
他还能说话 他是左撇子
He can still talk,and he's left-handed,
也就是说语言中枢在右脑
which means speech is in the right side.
你不知道25年前,Patrick的大脑是怎样重整的
You don't know how Patrick's brain reorganized itself 25 years ago.
万一右半脑只有一点点坏死呢
What if the right side is just a little dead.
也许偶尔还能进行神经原放电
Maybe he still has random neurons firing.
你不过在寻找难题 转移掉对自己的注意力
You're just looking for a puzzle to distract you from your own situation.
你说得对 他死了 我们回家吧
You're right. He's dead. Let's go home.
你们查出什么了吗?
What'd you find out?
会没事的 对吗?
It's going to be ok?
- 我很抱...- 是的!
- I'm sor-,- Yes!
这是什么?
What's this?
钢琴
Piano.
这是什么?
What's this?
他显然丧失了...
He's obviously lost use--
闭嘴
Shut up.
弹奏音乐需要运用整个大脑
Music is a global process.
只有半个大脑是弹不了钢琴的
Can't play the piano with half a brain.
这表明了什么?
What's it mean?
表明他的右半脑状况一直很糟
It means the right side of his brain has always sucked.
与当前发生的现象无关
It means it's not relevant to what's going on now.
这么说 是自身免疫疾病
Wow, then it's autoimmune.
是的 问题是 我们该拿它怎么办?
Yeah. Question is, what do we do about it?
很可能是可治疗的病症
Most likely ones we can fix.
结节性多动脉炎,多发性大动脉炎或肉样瘤
Polyarteritis nodosa, Takayasu, or sarcoid.
我去展开治疗
I'll start treatment.
我说的不是这个...好吧
Not what I was talking about, but yeah.
动手去干吧
You do that.
轮到你了?
Your turn?
你非得这样吗?
Do you have to do that?
你是指贬低大家的好意
You mean cheapen everyone's attempt at a human moment
侦测慰问背后的动机?
by identifying the real calculations that go into it?
- 是的,- 是 我是
Yeah. Yeah, I do.
你要死了 我很难过
I'm sorry you're dying.
我要拥抱你
I'm gonna hug you.
有什么想说的吗?
Anything to say?
如果你想捏我屁股 可别做任何
Well, if you're considering grabbing my ass, don't start anything...
你完成不了的动作
You can't finish.
既然我们还站在这里 介意就地开工吗?
Well, as long as we're just standing here, do you mind if we work?
孩子的治疗进行得怎么样了?
How's the kid's treatment going?
你在哭吗?
Are you crying?
没有 呼吸速率上升
No. Respiration rate's up.
癫痫平息了 状况很好
Seizures are calming down. It's all good.
对要进行的下个步骤 算不上好
Not for what I'm gonna do next.
用不了下一步了
But there is no next.
他会没事的
He's gonna be fine.
除非他想跟四岁的尿床儿童一样
Only if he wants to remain a four-year-old who wets his bed.
对他没别的办法了
There's nothing else for him.
有更好的
There's better.
谢谢你的拥抱
Thanks for the hug.
现在是深更半夜
It's the middle of the night.
你知道我在睡觉
You knew I'd be asleep.
电话铃也一样会吵醒你
Phone would've woken you up just as much.
再说 打电话我又看不到你穿什么
And I can't see what you're wearing on the phone.
我那智商55的病人,得了多发性大动脉炎综合症
My patient with the 55 IQ has Takayasu syndrome.
非常罕见
Very uncommon.
多发于亚洲妇女身上
Happens mostlyin Asian women.
你知道多发性大动脉炎可以用类固醇治疗
Takayasu is manageable with steroids, which you already know.
所以我猜你来有别的原因
So I assume you're here for something else.
我的病人还出现了严重的癫痫症状
My patient also has significant seizure problems.
可以用抗惊厥药控制
Also manageable with anti-convulsant medication.
是 如果一直使用抗惊厥药
Yes, and if he kept takinghis anti-convulsant medication,
他可以继续进行钢琴巡演
he could go back on tour and play the piano.
或者 大脑半球切除术完全
But...a hemispherectomy would completely
消除右半脑的癫痫
stop the right brain seizure activity
他就再不需要服用抗惊厥药了
and he would no longer need to take his anti-convulsant medication.
你想切除他半个大脑
You wanna remove half his brain.
右半脑 切除左半脑就太没责任心了
The right half, it would be irresponsible to remove the left.
要恢复功能犯不着切除半个大脑
You don't remove half a brainand gain function.
又不是我的大脑
Not my brain.
但他的呢 谁知道?
But his? Who knows?
听着 比方说我是Patrick的左半脑
Look, let's say that I'm the left side of Patrick's brain.
我思维敏捷 风度翩翩 英俊迷人
I'm quick-witted, I'm charming, I'm great looking.
而你是他的右半脑
You're the right side of his brain.
无用 腐朽 受损
You're useless, old, damaged.
我们去酒吧喝上一杯
We go to a bar for a drink.
我本该大施手段 勾引辣妹
Now, I have the mad skills to be scoring all the hot babes,
却不得不忙着擦你留下腮帮子的口水
but instead I'm spending my time wiping drool off your chin
还要确保你不去吃桌布
and making sure you don't eat the table cloth.
父亲打算怎么做?
What's the father wanna do?
不知道
I don't know.
去叫醒他吧
So go wake him up.
House 我很难过
House. I'm so sorry.
忘记我是将死之人了?
Forgot I was dying, huh?
需要我的话 我随时都在
I'm here if you need me.
我需要你
I need you.
对男人的一丁点儿同情
One small feel for man.
给男同胞一个饱满屁股
One giant ass for mankind.
谢谢
Thanks.
祝你在波士顿好运
Good luck in Boston.
给祈愿基金会打电话,(帮助病童梦想成真的基金会)
Call the make a wish foundation.
Foreman医生刚还在这儿
Dr.Foreman was just here.
癫痫症状几乎消失了
Seizures have most completely gone away.
也就是说我们明后天就可以回家了
Says we might be able to go home in the next day or two.
太感谢你们了
Thank you so much.
我认为应该切除你儿子的右半边大脑
I think we should remove the right side of your son's brain.
我以为你们治好他了
I thought you fixed him.
他看起来象治好的样子吗?
Does he look fixed?
右半脑能使他走直线
Right side of his brain was keeping him walking straight.
除此之外 事故后它就一直是累赘
Other than that, it's been dead weight ever since the accident.
如果移除掉 癫痫就会彻底消失
If we remove it, seizures would stop completely.
但是癫痫几乎察觉不到
But the seizures are hardly noticeable.
不会折磨Patrick
They don't bother Patrick.
但是没有癫痫
But without the seizures,
左半脑就有可能正常运作
the left side would have a chance to actually function.
可以学习新的动作
It could learn to do new things.
但是 他再也弹不了钢琴了
Only bummer...he'd never play the piano again.
不行 钢琴是他的一切
No, the piano is everything.
不是说 他能为航空航天局工作
I'm not saying he'd ever work for NASA,
但翻转夹肉饼肯定没问题
but flipping burgers isn't out of the question.
我不介意照顾他 让他去弹钢琴
Well, I don't mind taking care of him so he can play the piano.
是的 实际上你很幸运
No, you're actually lucky.
不用看着孩子长大成人
You don't have to watch your kid grow up.
不用放手给他们自由
You don't have to let go.
你就这么评价我?
You trying to make this about me?
我爱我儿子!
I love my son!
不管他什么样
Just the way he is.
他是马戏团的猴子
He's a monkey grinder at the circus.
- 他费劲千辛万苦才能有此...- 猴子也一样
- He's worked hard to get where he-,- So does the monkey.
钢琴不过是神经学上的意外
The piano is a neurological accident.
他有天赋
He has a gift.
而我能给他生命
I'm offering him a life.
这取决于你
It's up to you.
我已从House的集落刺激因子中,分离出癌蛋白
I've isolated the cancer proteins in House's csf.
该行动了
'Bout time.
如果他适宜进行杜克试验,就不能让他去波士顿
We can't let him goto Boston if he qualifies for the Duke trial.
你想做吗?
You wanna do it?
该死
Damn.
他没有异常磷酸化Tau蛋白
He's negative for protein phf.
不符合试验要求
He doesn't qualify.
那是什么?
What's that?
不该在这里出现
That shouldn't be there.
Patrick.
Patrick
你好 爸爸
Hello, papa.
Patrick 我有话想问你
Patrick, I have a question for you.
什么?
Yes?
你快乐吗?
Are you happy?
House 开门!
House, open up!
开门 这很重要!
Open up, it's important!
我的航班三小时后就起飞了
I've got a flight in three hours.
你没得癌症
You don't have cancer.
而是免疫球蛋白G和M出现了异常
There was abnormal presence of IGG and IGM indicating--
我没得神经梅毒 核磁共振没查出毛病
I don't have neurosyphilis. My MRI showed nothing-
你脑袋里不过长了个梅毒瘤
It's a gumma in your brain.
这东西没长在肝脏实在是罕见
It's very rare not to be in the liver,
很高兴我没跟你睡过 但是...
and I'm really glad we never slept together--
你会用避孕套的
You would've used a condom.
我没有梅毒
And I don't have syphilis.
- 我没有检查出性病,- 做了荧光螺旋体抗体试验
- My VDRL was negative-,- we did an FTA antibody test,
性病的诊断出现了假阴性
the VDRL was a false negative.
你不会死!
You're not going to die!
你只需静脉注射抗生素!
All you need is iv antibiotics!
你们把结果送到麻省总医院去了?
Did you send these results to mass general?
- 当然,- 你们这些白痴
- Of course.- You idiots.
我们刚跟你说你死不了
We just told you you're not gonna die.
你该跟Cameron亲热一下才是
You should be making out with Cameron.
你知道不是癌症?
You knew it wasn't cancer?
我肯定是癌症
I was sure it was cancer.
那你为什么不庆祝?
Then why aren't you celebrating?
因为这他妈的不是我的病历
Because it wasn't my damn file!
你伪造癌症?
You faked cancer?
真正的病人这会儿在Witherspoon医院
The real patient is in the Wither spoon wing.
欢迎随时告诉他妻子他死不了
Feel free to tell his wife that he's not gonna die,
但他在欺骗她
but he is cheating on her.
那你为什么想让我们认为你...
Why would you want us to think that you--
我没有
I didn't!
我不过想让波士顿那些家伙,以为我得了癌症
I wanted the guys in Boston to think that I had cancer.
他们以为我得了癌症,就会把绝妙的药注入
I wanted the guys who were gonna implant a cool drug right
我大脑的快乐中枢
into the pleasure center of my brain to think that I had cancer.
你假装生癌 就为了得到快感?
You faked cancer to get high?
我要去睡了
I'm going to bed.
你说得对
You're right.
我不喜欢你
I don't like you.
当然 因为我现在死不了
Sure, now that I'm not dying.
听说Patrick的大脑半球切除术进行得很好
I heard Patrick's hemispherectomy went well.
他挺过手术了
He survived the surgery.
现在还没醒
He's unconscious.
你有多消沉?
How depressed are you?
我不消沉
I'm not depressed.
你假装生癌
You faked cancer.
过个门诊手续而已
It was an outpatient procedure.
我很好奇
I was curious.
你对海洛因就不好奇吗?
Are you curious about heroin?
去年圣诞晚会后就失去好奇心了
Not since last year's Christmas party.
虽然这违你的天性 但别小题大做行吗?
I know this goes against your nature, but can we not make too much of this?
你让人们误以为你要死了
You made people think that you were going to die.
不是我迫他们的!
I didn't make them!
我想把这事掩藏起来的
I tried to hide it.
但你们这些白痴就爱多管闲事
But you idiots needed to get into my business.
我肯定会后悔问你 可你在笑什么?
I'm sure I'll regret asking, but why are you laughing?
真够讽刺的
It's ironic.
我肯定会后悔问你 但是为什么...
I'm sure I'll regret asking,but why--
癌症病人不如你想的那么容易消沉
Depression in cancer patients is not as common as you think.
让人们难过的不是死亡
It's not the dying that gets to people.
而是孤独地死去
It's the dying alone.
有亲朋好友陪伴的病人表现良好
The patients with family, with friends, they tend to do okay.
你没得癌症
You don't have cancer.
你有在乎你的人
You do have people who give a damn.
所以说你在干嘛呢?
So what do you do?
假冒癌症 将关心你的人推开
You fake the cancer, then push the people who care away.
因为他们烦死人了
Because they're boring.
回你的酒店房间去 嘲笑个够
Go home to your hotel room and laugh at that irony.
从小事着手吧 House
Start small, House.
抓住机会
Take a chance.
并不需要在脑袋上扎针
Maybe something that doesn't involve sticking stuff in your brain.
跟朋友吃个匹萨
Pizza with a friend.
看个电影
A movie.
诸如此事
Something.
看着我的手指
Follow my finger.
知道自己名字吗?
Do you know your name?
他的言语中枢在右半脑
His speech center was on the right side.
要过一会才能说话
It'll be a while before he's talking.
他除了向远方凝视 什么都没干
He hasn't really done anything except to stare off into the distance.
他得过会才能...
He'll take some time to...
哦
Oh, uh...
你扣上了衬衫纽扣
you buttoned your shirt.
他看起来很快乐
He looks happy.